So there are two ways we're going to look at being able to represent a graph.
The first one is going to be an adjacency matrix, the other one will be an adjacency list.
So let's bring up a graph and we're going to represent this in an adjacency matrix.
So we'll start by looking at this a vertex.
It has two edges with E and B, so we'll say A has edges with B and E, and we'll just put ones in those
boxes there.
And of course, A cannot have an edge with itself.
So we'll put a zero in that one and that it does not have an edge with C and D.
So we'll put zeros in there.
Now, let's look at B, it has edges with A and C so B.
Has edges with ANC and the rest will be zeros.
I'll just finish building this out like this to complete our matrix.
So this axis represents the actual vertex, this axis is the items it has an edge with.
So now one of the things that's interesting about an adjacency matrix we had mentioned that a can't
point to a will also be can't point to B and so on.
You're always going to have this 45 degree line of zeros.
And if you have a bi directional matrix like we have here, you will always have a mirror image on each
side of this 45 degree line that looks like that.
But this is only if these are bi directional, so let's change one of these two directional and take
a look at that.
We have a connection between A and B, so in the matrix, that is a connects to B, that's one.
B connects back to A that has a one.
But if we remove the edge that points from B to A and we changed this to a zero.
Now we have lost our symmetry across that 45 degree line.
So let's change the edge on the graph back to being bi directional and then we'll change it in the matrix.
And now it is symmetrical.
So another thing that you can have with your edges is that they can be weighted.
So if they're weighted in an adjacency matrix, we will just store these weights in the matrix like
this instead of having once.
OK, let's put that back.
And that is our quick overview of an adjacency matrix.