So now let's look at creating an adjacency list.
So an adjacency list is just another way of representing a graph, and we'll do this by using a hash
map.
So let's look at the Vertex A it has edges with B and E.
So when the hash map, we would represent this as a key value pair like this.
The vertex itself a is the key, and then the value is going to be an array list that has all of the
edges.
So notice the double quotes are used here.
That means there are strings, not chars, so you could put words in here instead of letters.
So now let's go around this graph and we'll move over to be.
It has edges with A and C C has edges with B and D.
D has edges with CNE, and then finally, EA has edges with Andy.
So this hash map on the right is just going to be another way of representing this graph on the left.
And that is our quick overview of an adjacency list.