So now we're going to look at the big O of graphs.
I'm going to bring up the graph that we've been using.
And we've looked at two ways of representing this graph and adjacency matrix and an adjacency list,
and we're going to look at the big O of both.
So first, we'll look at space complexity.
So if we have a vertex like a with an adjacency list, we're going to store that vertex and then we're
going to store each one of the edges in an adjacency matrix.
We store those edges.
But we also have to store everything that it is not connected to all of these zeros.
And that is a big advantage of the adjacency list.
So for space complexity, the adjacency matrix is o of the number of vertices squared in the adjacency
list is the number of vertices, plus the number of edges.
So from a space complexity perspective, the adjacency list is better.
So let's bring back our graph, and let's say we're going to add a vertex.
We're not adding an edge yet.
We'll look at that in a moment.
We're just adding a vertex, and it is not connected to anything with an edge yet.
So let's bring these back up and we'll look at the adjacency list first.
Adding a vertex is just a matter of doing this with the adjacency matrix.
We have to do this.
So the adjacency matrix is going to be stored in a two dimensional array.
As soon as you make those arrays bigger, you have to create new arrays that are bigger, and recreating
those arrays is very inefficient.
So from a big ole perspective, the adjacency matrix is the number of vertices squared every time you
add a vertex, whereas with an adjacency list, it's a of one to add a vertex.
So the adjacency list is much more efficient at doing this.
So let's bring our graph back, and we're going to add an edge between B and our new Vertex F like this.
And let's bring these back up and look at the adjacency list.
First, in order to do this will add an edge that goes from B to F like this.
And then one that goes from F to be like this with the adjacency matrix.
We just go in and change this from a zero to a one.
And then we do the same thing here.
And that adds that edge between FNB.
So both the adjacency matrix and the adjacency list are zero of one to add an edge.
So let's bring back our graph and look at what it would take to remove this edge.
We'll bring these back up and start with the adjacency list in order to remove the edge between B and
F..
We're going to go find B and finding a key and a hash map is O of one.
But once we find B, we have to iterate through that entire array list and find F and then remove it.
Then we'll come down to F and do the same thing here.
Go through this array list.
And remove be.
With an adjacency matrix, we just come here and change the one to a zero.
Change this one to a zero.
And that edge is removed.
So this is a situation where the adjacency matrix outperforms the adjacency list.
The adjacency matrix is of one.
But the adjacency list you have to go through, all of the edges in a particular vertex might have a
thousand edges, and you'd have to go through the entire array list to remove the edge.
So now let's bring back our graph and we will remove a vertex like that.
So let's bring this back up and we'll start with the adjacency list.
So when you're looking at this, this looks pretty simple that you would just remove this.
But we're also going to have to come here and go through this entire array list here and see if there
are any f's.
Then we're going to come down here and do the same thing with this array list and so wand through the
entire adjacency list.
So you're going to have to touch every vertex and every edge.
There is a way to do this more efficiently if you have bi directional edges, and we'll go over that
when we do our method for remove vertex because we're going to create our graph with bi directional
edges.
So now let's look at this with an adjacency matrix.
In order to remove that f vertex, we have to do this and rewrite the arrays.
So this is also very inefficient when we remove a vertex from an adjacency matrix.
So the big o of the adjacency matrix is going to be o of the number of vertices squared.
The adjacency list is O of V plus e and other words, you have to touch every vertex and every edge.
So in this course, we're just going to create an adjacency list, and I want to talk a little bit more
about why an adjacency list is typically better than an adjacency matrix.
So we talked about with an adjacency matrix that we're not just storing.
The connections are the ones.
We also have to store all of the zeros.
All of the things that were not connected to this becomes incredibly inefficient when you have a very
large graph.
So say you have something like Facebook.
And we'll say for easy figuring that Facebook has a billion active users.
While you would have a graph that has instead of five like we're showing here, there would be a billion
items across the top and a billion items down the left side of this graph.
Even if each of the billion users had a thousand friends, you would have literally a million zeros
in that graph for every one.
So that would be incredibly inefficient.
So that is why in this course, we are going to use an adjacency list and that is graph big O.