So now let's build our ad edge method, and Ad Edge is just going to take two vertices, which will
look like this.
And then we add an edge between them.
And in the adjacency list that will look like this.
So let's bring this down to the bottom and write the code for this.
So we'll call this ad edge will pass it, the two vertices that we're creating an edge between and for
the next line of code, what I'm going to do is I'm going to break it into two pieces.
So we're going to say adjacency list dot get.
We're going to pass it vertex one.
In this case, that's going to be a down here.
And when we run this get method, what is going to return is this ArrayList.
So we pass it the key and it returns the value.
This is just like we did with the get method and the hash table S. That's doing the same thing here.
So since we've returned an ArrayList, we can now use the methods that apply to an array list so we
can say Dot Ad, and this dot ad applies to the array list and we'll pass it Vertex two, which is B,
which does this.
So we'll do this exact same thing again, except switching Vertex two and Vertex one, and then we'll
add Vertex one to this array list, and that adds the edge between A and B.
So these two lines of code here can only be run if both of the vertices that we're adding the edge between
exist.
If all the vertices that we have in our graph are a and B like we have here, then obviously we cannot
add an edge between A and C.
So we're going to wrap these two lines of code with an if statement like this that says if Vertex one
and Vertex two both exist, they're not equal to null.
Only then do we run these next two lines of code.
And if the conditional in this if statement is true and we've added, the edge will also want to return
true.
If the conditional in the statement is false, we'll skip past that and we'll return false.
So that is our entire ad edge method.
Now let's flip over to Intel AIG and take a look at this.
So there is the add edge method that we just created, and I'll come up here to this tab where we have
our main method.
And with this line here, we'll create a new graph.
And then with these two lines, we'll add those vertices A and B, and then we'll print this out and
I'll run this.
So you can see up here that we have our two vertices, A and B, but we don't have an edge between them
yet, so I'm going to come up here and add a line.
And with this line will add an edge between A and B, and that will once again print out the graph with
this line here, so I'll run this.
And you can see now that we have an edge between A and B.
And that is our method for Ad Edge.