So now we're going to write our method to remove an edge that's going to look like this if we remove
an edge between A and B and the diagram at the bottom, it's going to look like that.
And in the adjacency list on top, removing the edge is going to look like this.
So let's move this down to the bottom, and we'll bring these back, and then we'll write the code to
remove those.
We'll start our coat out like this.
Remove Edge will pass at the two vertices that were removing an edge between.
So with this next line of code, I'm going to do the same thing we did in the last video where we break
the line of code into two parts.
So first, we're going to say adjacency list dot get Vertex one.
So Vertex one is a.
And when we do the get it returns the array list.
And because of that, we can now run methods on that array list so we can say Dot remove Vertex two,
and that removes that.
Now we'll do the same thing going the other way, and in this case will remove Vertex one.
Like that, and that removes the edge.
And just like we had in the ad edge method, we couldn't add an edge unless both vertices existed.
Similarly, with this method, remove edge, both of the vertices have to exist, so we'll have to wrap
these two lines of code.
And this if statement that checks to make sure both of those vertices exist, it is only then that we
can run the next two lines and after we run, those will return true if the conditional in the if statement
equates to false will skip the if statement.
And we will return false.
So that is our entire method for removing Edge will look at this in a moment in intelligence.
And when we do, we'll create this graph and then we'll run remove edge between A and B, and then the
graph will look like this.
So now let's flip over to Intel AJ and take a look at this.
So there is our remove edge method that we just created there added to our graph class.
And I'll come up here to our main class that has our main method.
And with this line here, we'll create a new graph called my graph.
And then with these three lines here will create the three vertices A, B and C, and then with these
three lines will connect all three of the vertices to each other.
And then with this line, we will print that out.
So I'll run this.
So you can see up here that we have three vertices A, B and C, and they all have edges with each other.
Someone to come over here and add a line.
So this line here will remove the edge between the A and the B vertices, and then with this line here,
we will print that out.
So I'll run this.
And you can see that are a and B vertices no longer have edges with each other.
And that is our method for removing Edge.