So now we're going to create our Remove Vertex method.
I'm going to bring up a graph like this, and let's say we're going to remove the D vertex if we're
going to remove that.
We also need to remove all of the edges with D like this.
And then we can remove the Vertex seven to bring D back like this and put everything back the way it
was.
So this graph would be represented by this adjacency list, and I'll just keep that on the screen since
that's what we're actually working with.
In the big old video, I talked about an efficiency that we could use when removing a vertex when all
of our edges are bi directional.
And we're able to use that efficiency because of what is stored in this adjacency list.
If De has edges with A, B and C, we know if they're bi directional edges that A, B and C also have
edges with D.
So even if we had a graph that had a thousand vertices on it, we know that only these three have edges
that connect back to D.
So what we can do is loop through this array list, and we know that a in its array list must have an
edge back to D and then we can remove that and we can keep looping through that array list at the bottom.
And we know that B must have an edge back to D, and we know that C must have an edge back to D.
And like I said, if we had a thousand vertices, we don't have to visit any of those other vertices
to remove the edge back to D. We only have to visit these three.
Now that we've removed all of the edges going back to RD, we can come down here and remove the vertex.
And that leaves us with a graph that looks like this.
So now that we've walked through that, let's start writing the code.
We'll call this remove Vertex, and then we're just going to pass this the vertex that we want to remove.
So the first thing we'll do is this will say, if adjacency list get well past us, the vertex, if
it's null, that means that the vertex is not in the graph.
If that's the case, we're just going to return false.
Otherwise, we know the vertex is on the graph and the first thing we want to do is create a for loop
to loop through that array list.
So we'll do that like this, and we'll walk through all of this here in a second.
But we're going to pass this the vertex adjacency list, yet we're going to pass that to Vertex.
So I'm going to focus and just on this line of code and bring this up.
So remember when we do adjacency list dot get pass at the vertex, that vertex is D and what it returns
is this ArrayList.
So this is what we're looping through in this for loop.
So when I call this variable here, other vertex, because this is the other vertex that we need to
go to to remove the edge that goes back to DX.
Some of bringing back the rest of our code like this.
So I'm going to break this next line down into two steps, we're going to say adjacency list Typekit.
Other Vertex.
And remember, that's going to return an array list so we can use the methods associated with a release
and we can say dot remove the vertex that we want to remove from that array less.
So now let's look at just this line of code.
Remember that this line is inside of the four loops.
I'm going to do this and walk through what this does.
So the first time through the for loop other Vertex is going to be that a variable that I have highlighted
in the vertex at the bottom there.
So the adjacency lists dot jet is going to give us this vertex, the dot removed vertex is going to
remove D.
And then we move through the for loop and do that here.
Now other vertex is going to be B and then we remove D and then we do it again.
Here other vertex will be C here and then we remove that.
So let's bring back the rest of our code like this.
Now we've removed all of those edges that go back to.
Now we can actually remove the Vertex DX.
Like this so adjacency list dot remove.
We pass at this vertex and that is going to do this.
Which gives us a graph that looks like this.
Now there's one thing left to add to our code, and that is to return true because we are returning
a Boolean.
So that's the entire method there.
We'll look at this method in a moment and intelligence, and when we do, we'll create this graph and
then we'll run the remove vertex method to remove the D vertex like that.
And that will leave us with an adjacency list that looks like this.
So now let's flip over to Intel AJ and take a look at this.
So there is our remove vertex method there that we just created, that I'll come up here to our main
class that contains our main method, and then with this line here we create a new graph called my graph.
With these four lines, here we create the four vertices A, B, C and D.
And then with these lines here, we'll add all of the edges that we had in the diagram.
And with this line here, we'll print this out.
So I'll run this.
And this prints out our graph up here.
So now I'm going to come over here and I'm going to add this line of code, and this will remove that
Vertex D and then with this line here, we will print this out.
So I'll run this.
So you can see that the Vertex Rd and all of the edges to D have been removed.
So it looks like we have a working method for remove Vertex.